# ARMANDAS BARKAUSKAS

Address: 51 Grafton Street, CV1 2HX Linked In:

Mobile: +44 7914 603 504 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/armandas-barkauskas">https://www.linkedin.com/in/armandas-barkauskas</a>

E-mail: armandas.bark@gmail.com Portfolio:

https://github.com/armandasalmd?tab=repositories

#### **PROFILE**

Highly competent full-stack web application developer with **1 year** of industrial **experience** working with most contemporary web technologies. Have in-depth web project lifecycle understanding and capable at all aspects of development from requirements analysis to its execution through teamworking. Currently **seeking for a long-term graduate position as software engineer**.

#### **SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE**

## **LANGUAGES & TECHNOLOGIES**

<u>Confident:</u> ASP.NET, AdobeXD & Figma, NodeJS, Python, ReactJS, TypeScript
<u>Intermediate:</u> C++, CSS/Sass, Docker, Entity Framework, MongoDB, SQL Server

• Beginner: Android Studio, Django, Redis, WPF, Xamarin

OTHER SKILLS: Agile/Scrum, Azure DevOps, Autho, CircleCI, jQuery, Git, KnockoutJS, Linux Bash, Postman, Unit Testing (JEST)

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## 2020/07 - 2021/07 JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT PINEWOOD TECHNOLOGIES

- Develop and maintain custom data-centric web applications using ASP.NET, C#.NET, LINQ and Services with Agile/SCRUM methodology
- Maintained and built various web pages, implementing UI requirements using ASP.NET, JS/jQuery, knockoutJS and MS SQL as the backend
- Received full training including various workshops, presentations, individual UX project
- **Supported by highly experienced mentor**, which regularly gave me reflections and taught me to write maintainable software
- Collaborated with a team of 6 interns to develop an internal dashboard project awarding me with soft skills like **teamwork**, **shared decision making**, **and work organization**

#### 2016 – 2018/05 SELF-EMPLOYED PERSONAL TUTOR OF MATHS AND IT

- Developed **communication skill** while attempting to explain complex topics simplified
- **Planning** and organizing lesson topics in a strict schedule

#### **EDUCATION**

#### 2018 – Present Computer Science BSC at Coventry University

- 2<sup>nd</sup> vear average **84%** (1<sup>st</sup> class)
- Relevant modules: Software engineering, OOP, Database systems, Computer architecture

# 2006 – 2018 HIGH SCHOOL CERTIFICATE AT "KTU ENGINEERING LYCEUM"

• Relevant classes: **Math**, **IT**, **English** with **100%**, **100%** and **86%** results from the state exams respectively. Certificate score **equivalent A\*A\*B** 

#### 2014 – 2016 PROGRAMMING FOUNDATION COURSE (2 YEAR) AT "JKM-KTU"

- Graduation project score: 10.0 (available in portfolio)
- Learning outcomes: C++, C#, JavaScript, Java, Graph Theory

### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Full personal project experience can be found in my GitHub portfolio here (full link above).

### 2019/09 – Present NOTE TAKING/SHARING WEB APP "NOTEX" - notex-app.com

A full-stack project spanning across 3 separate repositories with more than a year spent developing it. The product achieved MVP target recently, but app has huge plans over improvements and new epic stories such as "public article sharing community" like medium.com.

## **Key achievements:**

- UX/UI designing with **Figma** and feedback collection before development
- Automated CI/CD using **CircleCI** and **Docker** containers
- Shared 3<sup>rd</sup> party AUTH service integration across 2 backend applications
- **TypeScript API** server development with Unit Testing (Jest) + **MongoDB**/Mongoose ORM mimicking **Domain-Driven-Design** (DDD) principles
- ReactJS mastery
  - Antd UI library
  - o Mobile first Less/CSS UI components using BEM standards
  - o **Redux** state management
  - o React Hooks, HOC
- **ASP.NET Core** API server to address "article community" domain problem.
  - o Cross API communication with auth
  - o Dependency Injection
  - o Most up to date **EF Core** implementation over **SQL Server**
  - o **RediSearch** search cache integration for optimised user experience
  - o **Postman** API documentation

### 2017/06 – 2018/02 ANDROID APP "WEEKLY ROUTINE" - tiny.cc/joyzdz

Productive calendar type time management app. Standalone Android Application deployed over Google Play. To this day, app has **75 active users**. The app itself made more productive and disciplined in my studies.

### **Key achievements:**

- Applying Material design patterns (UX)
- Object **parsing** to JSON, saving to memory
- Deploying the app to Google Play

- Building .axml layouts, animating
- Model **ERD**; reduce, map, sort methods
- Real-time **debugging** call-stack, variables

References available upon request.